Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
It looks like the relationship
between Noble Consort Lumiere and you
is truly extraordinary.
My Lady, you...
Petunia, you've been a servant in my palace, but
I never realized your thoughts reach so far above your station.
I'm a servant to Your Highness.
My only thought is the well-being of Your Highness.
But as a servant in the palace,
my greatest loyalty is solely to His Majesty.
If I offended Your Highness, I beg Your Highness's forgiveness.
If loyalty to His Majesty might offend me,
doesn't that place me in a position of disloyalty?
Your Majesty, please allow me to ask her a few questions.
Petunia, no matter what happens today,
you cannot return to the Palace of Eternal Longevity
to serve me anymore.
As long as I serve the palace,
no matter which concubine I serve,
I would go through fire and water
without hesitation for my mistress.
Excellent! After all, we are mistress and servant.
You claim to reveal my private matters today.
You must have known this is the last time you will ever serve me.
I hope you fulfilled your daily duties as my servant.
Tell me, before you left my palace today,
did you dust the glazed flower vase
on the red sandalwood table in my main hall?
Yes, I did.
Nonsense.
There never was a glazed flower vase
on Her Highness's red sandalwood table.
The vase is made of gray jade.
I misremembered, it is a jade vase.
It seems that Petunia lacks a good memory.
It must have been a great effort for you
to remember the pattern on Dr. Wen's cuff.
I remember! It is a gray jade vase, without any doubt.
There was never a flower vase
on the red sandalwood table in the main hall.
You are my servant,
yet instead of keeping your mind on your actual job,
you care more about which doctor put his hand on mine
and the patterns on the cuff!
If any other servant ran into the same situation,
they wouldn't even dare to look.
Why did you pay so much attention to every single detail?
Your reason for doing so is indeed suspicious.
This is such a great matter and
has been the only thing on my mind.
How could I pay attention to any other duties?
I think, if Dr. Wen and Noble Consort Lumière really had a secret affair,
they would take every precaution.
How did Petunia manage to see them every single time?
And so vividly?
Does Petunia
pay unusual attention to the behavior of her mistress?
What a maid. Look at yourself.
How dare you keep a prying eye on Noble Consort Lumière!
Your Majesty,
I find this matter quite odd.
There must be someone behind this maid.
We can't trust what she is saying.
There might be a greater conspiracy yet to emerge.
I'm confused.
Noble Lady Délice lives in the Pavilion of Twining Reeds,
and Petunia is a servant of the Palace of Eternal Longevity.
Everyone is aware that
Lady Délice has always been disrespectful
to Noble Consort Lumière.
Why would a servant of the Palace of Eternal Longevity
ally herself with Noble Lady Délice
to expose this matter to Your Majesty?
If what Petunia said is true,
Noble Consort Lumière might "bring a vicious hand down" on Petunia.
Then nobody would ever learn about
this filthy matter in the harem.
So it was reasonable for Petunia
to seek help from Noble Lady Délice.
I've heard that people who worship the Buddha have a compassionate heart.
They wouldn't even step on an ant.
Noble Consort Lumière practiced Buddhism
at the Temple of Pure Dew to pray for the Great Qing.
She also received the Buddha's blessing
to give birth to imperial heirs.
Why would she do something so indecent?
The Buddha's temple is a place to purify one's heart.
But Zhen Huan's nature is so impure
that she committed profane acts
even during her time at the temple.
Lady Délice, Pure Dew is a sacred temple of the Great Qing.
Aren't you afraid your venomous, nonsensical slander
will incur the Buddha's punishment?
His Majesty the Emperor!
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Without a single quiet day in the harem, how can I be at peace?
We disturbed Your Majesty's peace.
I entreat Your Majesty's forgiveness.
Tell me, what is all this commotion about?
Your Majesty, I am exposing Noble Consort Lumière's adultery
which desecrates the harem.
You wretch!
Nonsense!
I swear it on my life, Your Majesty!
Every word I say is true.
Noble Lady Délice swore a dreadful oath in front of everyone.
She is so serious;
I can't help but think she has her reasons.
I only hope to eliminate misunderstandings,
if there are any.
Otherwise, rumors might compound
and damage Noble Consort Lumière's good name.
Very well, I will hear you out.
If there is a word of falsehood, I won't forgive you.
I have evidence to show that
Noble Consort Lumière has a secret relationship with Dr. Wen.
After Noble Consort Lumière left the palace,
Dr. Wen visited her in the Temple of Pure Dew frequently.
They were usually unaccompanied in her room.
If Your Majesty does not believe me,
you can bring in the nun from the temple for further inquiry.
She's already in the palace.
It's Your Majesty's decision whether to summon the nun or not.
Bring her in.
Jade, how's Lord XVII's health?
He's much better.
Where's My Lady?
I haven't seen her since I came back.
She went away with Mr. Jiang
and still hasn't returned.
Jade, I'm so glad you're here!
Lady Paix sent me to tell you
Lady Délice brought in a nun from the Temple of Pure Dew
to accuse Her Highness of committing adultery at the temple.
What?!
My Lady wants to know if you have any way to help.
It's best if you know someone from the temple
who can disprove what the nun says.
Accusing my sister of adultery?!
How can His Majesty believe this?
We have to find Moyan from the Temple of Pure Dew.
My Second Lady, we must be back
before the palace gates are locked.
All right. Xiao-Yunzi will go with me.
But you should stay here in case anything else goes wrong.
Alü, you are Noble Lady Paix's servant,
please meet us at the palace gates.
Understood.
- Xiao-Yunzi, let's hurry.
- Yes
Why are you in such a rush?
What's wrong?
Get out of my way!
It's my sister. I have to help her!
What's going on in the palace?
This humble nun is named Jingbai, from the Temple of Pure Dew.
Peace to Your Majesties.
Peace to Noble Consort Lumière.
It's been a long time since we last met.
I wonder if Noble Consort Lumière still remembers me?
Prioress Jingbai, you were able to make the trip to the palace.
You must be fully recovered from the flogging.
Thanks to Your Noble Highness's punishment,
I've learned that I must speak the truth.
I certainly hope so.
Please report what you know about the matter, Prioress Jingbai.
We don't want to disturb your practice.
Certainly.
Her Noble Highness showed no interest in interacting with the nuns
when she first came to the temple.
We could only regard her humbly from a distance.
There was an elder madam from the palace
who visited Her Highness quite often.
Aside from her, only a doctor surnamed Wen
visited frequently.
A few times I passed by Her Highness's residence
and saw the door was closed even during the day.
Her two servants stood guard outside the door.
I thought it was quite inappropriate,
and wanted to offer a word of caution.
However, Her Highness rebuked me over it.
So I couldn't say anything more.
Later on, to avoid the rumors floating around the temple,
Noble Consort Lumière claimed that she was ill
and moved away to Peak Lingyun with her servants.
I am not aware if Noble Consort Lumière and
Dr. Wen stayed in contact afterwards.
Prioress Jingbai, is the Dr. Wen you referred to
present in this hall at the moment?
Amitābha Buddha, it is this man right here before my eyes.
Are you sure you're not mistaken?
It's rare to have a male visitor at the Temple of Pure Dew.
Dr. Wen was a frequent visitor.
It's impossible for me to mistake him for someone else.
Your Majesty, I'm getting a headache listening to this.
I'd like to go back and rest.
Prioress, you said you're from the Temple of Pure Dew?
Thank you for asking, Noble Lady. I am.
Buddhist practitioners are accustomed to purity and calm.
It must have been difficult for you to
leave the temple and come to the palace.
Prioress, there's something I wish to trouble you with.
I want to offer a votive oil lamp to Buddha for fulfilling my prayer.
I'm wondering how many catties of oil would be appropriate.
Amitābha Buddha.
Monastic nuns do not easily step into
the "red dust of the secular world".
I once visited Baohua Hall in the palace two years ago
to deliver a handwritten copy of the Diamond Sutra.
Other than that, I haven't been to the palace.
My Lady, you are favored by His Majesty
and should therefore offer a weighty oil lamp.
But your rank is only Noble Lady...
I believe two to three catties per day will suffice.
Thank you for your trouble, Prioress.
Your Majesty, I will take my leave.
Your Majesty, were Dr. Wen's frequent visits to the temple
permitted by Your Majesty?
This would all be quite reasonable if
it was Your Majesty's order.
Your Majesty, Noble Consort Lumière was living at a remote residence,
but both Jade and Jinxi
can testify for me.
Her Highness and I are truly innocent.
Dr. Wen, do you think we're all fools?
We all know Jinxi and Jade
are trusted attendants of Consort Lumière.
How could their testimony be trusted?
Wen Shichu and Zhen Huan have been
bosom friends since childhood.
They exchanged loving glances once she entered the palace.
Wen Shichu secretly visited Zhen Huan after she left the palace.
They confessed their private feelings
and came up with a scheme to move to Peak Lingyun,
so they could interact intimately, like a married couple.
Even after Zhen Huan returned to the palace,
they've exhibited acts of indecency within the palace walls,
with no sense of shame!
Your Majesty, I have served in the palace for more than ten years.
Her Highness Noble Consort Lumière
is not the first mistress I've served.
And she is not the mistress I have served the longest.
There is no reason for me to be partial to Her Highness.
I want to say this impartially,
and with a calm and even temper:
Noble Consort Lumière and Dr. Wen do not have any private feelings.
Do you, or do you not?
Your Majesty, I do not.
Your Majesty, Noble Lady Délice has long held a
grudge against Noble Consort Lumière.
She's simply found some people to provide
false and collusive testimony.
Dr. Wen is fulfilling his duty as a doctor
by visiting Noble Consort Lumière frequently.
If people are allowed to gossip about that,
then we concubines who have received care from Dr. Wen
should all fear defamation.
That's enough.
I trust Noble Consort Lumière.
if Your Majesty truly wishes to clear Noble Consort Lumière's name,
and to prevent rumors in the days to come,
you should investigate this matter thoroughly.
Lumière gave birth to the imperial heirs for Your Majesty,
and she's also managing matters in the harem - both great and small.
Out of respect for her hard work
Your Majesty must thoroughly investigate,
thereby freeing Lumière from disturbing gossip.
Now you are concerned about your deep sisterhood.
When Noble Consort Lumière was in the Temple of Pure Dew
I didn't see you sending anyone to visit her.
It was Dr. Wen who put in the effort.
Noble Consort Lumière returned to the palace pregnant,
so she became pregnant outside the palace.
Your Majesty wasn't able to visit her very often.
As Prioress Jingbai said,
it was Dr. Wen who went frequently.
Then Noble Consort Lumière’s pregnancy…
Noble Lady Délice, are you implying
that the Prince and Princess are not the imperial heirs.
This matter concerns the state and the nation,
how can you make such irresponsible speculations?
Your Majesty mustn’t believe Noble Lady Délice's conjectures.
Your Majesty.
There is no basis for Noble Lady Délice's speculation.
You all enjoy echoing the hearsay.
I do not allow anyone to "chew their tongues" about this!
"Echoing the hearsay"?
Are you saying what Lady Délice speculated
has already been widely discussed in the palace?
When the ladies in the palace idle their days away,
they tend to embellish every falsehood they hear
and "chase the wind to catch the shadow."
Your Majesty need not pay it any heed.
Embellish every falsehood?
Then you tell me, what are these falsehoods?
If their repetition brings the harem to chaos,
as the head of the harem,
why didn’t you quell the rumors and restore peace?
Noble Consort Lumière was pregnant before returning
to the palace, and her children were born early.
Everyone said the origin of Noble Consort Lumière’s twins was unclear,
and that they do not carry Your Majesty's bloodline.
Such a rumor "soils the hearing."
I was reluctant to give it any consideration.
The cats startled Noble Consort Lumière at night,
causing her premature delivery.
Who could have foreseen that?
Besides, Noble Consort Lumière has always had a weak constitution.
Longyue was also born after only eight months.
Hence the rumors are false.
I too think so, Your Majesty.
Why did the cats in the palace pounce on someone for no reason?
And land exactly on
Noble Consort Lumière’s sedan chair?
If this was not an accident,
why didn’t Noble Consort Lumière investigate it afterwards?
Unless it was her own scheme
to hide that she was at the end of her pregnancy.
Your Majesty, on the day Her Highness gave birth,
I thought it was strange that,
before she passed out in pain,
Dr. Wen asked whether to save the mother, or babies.
I was wondering...
shouldn't this question have been asked of
Your Majesty and the Empress Dowager?
Why did he ask Her Highness?
I also heard the words "decades of affection"...
and "an undying heart"…
As the Empress, Your Majesty is head of the harem.
I dare to ask,
what’s the punishment for a concubine’s adultery?
Your Majesty,
Given Noble Consort Lumière is the mother of the Sixth Prince,
please grant her clemency.
Noble Consort Lumière became pregnant
outside the palace before she returned.
That was already suspicious.
Her only maids were Jinxi and Jade at that time.
In my opinion,
only heavy torture will yield the answers.
How dare you!
Torture usually leads to unjust convictions.
How can you abuse physical punishment to force a confession?
Your Majesties,
the only way out of this is to torture Jinxi and Jade severely,
or else,
Noble Consort Lumière and Dr. Wen must be made to suffer instead.
Flesh and skin are cheap.
How would people confess without torture?
If they receive all 72 punishments from the Department of Penalty
and still don't withdraw their statement,
maybe they speak some truth.
Aiyo, if they take all the 72 punishments,
they'll be disabled if they even live.
What's the point of that, just to prove them innocent?
Your Majesty, to protect the prestige of Her Noble Highness,
I am willing to withstand any punishment.
But, Noble Consort Lumière's health is precious as gold.
She can’t be left unattended.
I entreat Your Majesty to exempt Jade from the punishment.
Lumière, I know you have pity for Jinxi and Jade.
But if they are not tortured,
I am afraid that you will be in a difficult situation.
Even if you feel pity for them,
you must put up with it for now.
However, Jade has always accompanied you.
Why is she not present today?
Lord XVII has been sick for quite some days.
Jade requested that she take care of His Lordship
so she is currently not in the palace.
Your Majesty, if she was commanded to return immediately,
I'm afraid all the lords, and the imperial clan, would be disturbed.
This matter is not conclued yet; it should stay inside the harem.
It should stay inside the harem?
I have already been informed, Your Majesty.
Please forgive me, Your Majesty.
I entered the palace to pay my respects to the Empress Dowager.
But all the palaces were quiet,
except for a bustling crowd here.
So, I came to see what is going on.
While waiting outside, I didn't expect to hear all this.
As a member of the imperial clan,
I wish to vouch for Noble Consort Lumière,
the Prince, and the Princess.
Since Noble Consort Lumière entered the palace,
she has been diligently attending to everything herself.
So I'm willing to believe in Noble Consort Lumière's character.
Venerable Prince Shen usually
"directs his eyes over others' heads."
and avoids contact with the concubines.
How can Your Lordship speak of
Noble Consort Lumière's many merits?
"Attended to everything herself" -
sounds like Your Lordship saw it with your own eyes.
There's no need for me to personally see
Noble Consort Lumière doing everything herself.
Just look at how slim Noble Consort Lumière is.
You can tell how hard she's worked.
By contrast, Noble Lady Délice looks like a plump pearl.
We can tell that you've enjoyed a leisured life.
You...
Close your mouth!
It is all well and good to have Venerable Prince Shen's vouching.
But the Sixth Prince carries the imperial bloodline
and great expectations from His Majesty.
This is a matter concerning thousands of generations.
We must not proceed without being thorough.
Then tell me, what do you consider thorough?
I'm afraid we have to confirm it with a blood droplet test.
I have heard of this from the imperial doctors before.
The so-called blood droplet test
is to pierce each individual to obtain a drop of blood,
let the drops fall into the same bowl of water,
and observe if they diffuse into each other.
If they blend together this indicates a shared bloodline.
If not, there's no blood relationship between the individuals.
This is not a difficult method
but to pierce His Majesty's body for blood ...
I really dare not do so.
That definitely can not be performed.
How could we harm Your Majesty's "body of a dragon"?
Has Your Majesty considered
once Hongyan takes the blood droplet test,
even if he is proven the son of Your Majesty,
the relationship between you and Hongyan
will be impaired when he grows up and learns about it.
If Your Majesty really holds great expectations for Hongyan,
people will disparage him due to this incident.
It's exactly because His Majesty holds great expectations for the Sixth Prince
that he must do the test.
If we do not, isn't there a risk that
Your Majesty will give away - with open hands -
the entire territory to a mistaken heir?
I always thought there was deep affection between Your Majesty and myself.
Who would have thought that we would find ourselves here?
Had I known I would be subject to
such suspicion by Your Majesty,
I would rather have stayed at Peak Lingyun
to perish in a lonesome life.
Huan Huan,
with only one act,
I can clear your and the child's name.
If Your Majesty intends to do the test ...
it must mean that you do hold suspicion.
Since Your Majesty
suspects me of having a secret relationship with Dr. Wen,
Then Hongyan,
only needs to be tested with Dr. Wen's blood.
This way, it won't harm Your Majesty's "body of a dragon",
and will also attest to my and Hongyan's innocence.
Su Peisheng, bring the Sixth Prince here.
Yes.
You will prepare the materials for the blood droplet test.
Peace to Your Majesty from the Sixth Prince, Hongyan.
Your Majesty, the Sixth Prince...
Obtain one drop of his blood.
Your Majesty, once you do this,
even if Hongyan is proven to be your son by blood,
he will always be the subject of every gossiper -
calling him the prince whose bloodline was questioned by Your Majesty.
In the future ...
How will Hongyan establish himself under Heaven?
Be seated for now.
Su Peisheng.
Yes.
Wen Shichu.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, this is impossible!
This is absolutely impossible, Your Majesty!
Shameless! Zhen Huan! On your knees!
Your Majesty, I've done nothing wrong. Why should I kneel?
The diffusion of blood indicates a blood relation.
What do you have left to say for yourself?
Guards! Rip off the attire of a Noble Consort!
Banish her to the Cold Palace!
Throw that sinful child in with her!
Wen Shichu! Flogged to death immediately!
Who dares?!
I treated you generously.
Why do you ...
Why do you do this to me?
Your Majesty... Your Majesty.
You disappointed me so gravely.
See for yourself!
The water... Something must be wrong with the water.
Your Majesty, something's wrong with the water.
Your Majesty,
the water is the problem.
It can mix together anyone's blood.
Your Majesty, please examine it!
Your Majesty!
The water is the problem.
Your Majesty, the water is the problem!
It was meddled with!
Her Noble Highness is innocent, Your Majesty!
Your Majesty...
Your Majesty, it's impossible.
I am incapable of siring children.
How can Dr. Wen and Jinxi be blood-related to me?
I know.
Your Majesty, the water has a sour taste
because alum has been added.
Your Majesty, it was noted in the ancient medical texts that
"water with alum can mix the blood of unrelated father and son"
and that "water with oil cannot mix the blood,
even of related father and son."
Your Majesty, the viciousness
of this person's heart can now be fathomed.
In the interest of fairness,
it was the Empress who prepared the water.
Your Majesty, there's absolutely nothing wrong with the water I brought.
I am aware that you are knowledgeable about medicine.
If I had used this this trick
knowing it could be easily discovered,
wouldn't that have been too risky?
I'm not that foolish, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, as the saying goes,
"You can't catch tiger cubs without entering the tiger's lair".
Although risky, this trick was highly likely to work out.
Once it succeeded, everyone would deem
the Sixth Prince to be the son of imperial Dr. Wen.
Who would request a second test?
Your Majesty, I am wrongfully accused.
I trust Your Majesty will make a fair judgment.
I'm distinguished as the Empress,
why would I concoct such an unwise plot to frame Noble Consort Lumière?
Yes, Your Majesty is already the Empress.
What are you unsatisfied about?
Your Majesty, please make a clear-sighted judgment.
Your Majesty,
had I not discovered this in time,
Hongyan would have already been wrongfully executed,
even though he is your son.
I have always revered Your Majesty as the Empress.
I'm respectful towards you in every way.
I don't know how I offended the Empress
that I must suffer this fatal disaster.
Your Majesty, I have brought a fresh bowl of water.
There is nothing wrong with it.
Test again!
Yes.
Your Majesty,
please look.
The test has been completed.
Will this clear Your Majesty's suspicion?
Huan Huan,
I wrongfully attributed fault to you.
I won't hold any more doubt.
My standing is now as clear
as the light from the shadow.
Please sit.
Noble Lady Délice,
what do you have to say now?
Your Majesty, even if the Sixth Prince is indeed your son,
these three are all witnesses of the affecton
between Noble Consort Lumiere and Wen Shichu.
Will Your Majesty turn a blind eye to that?
I dare not lie, Your Majesty! I dare not lie!
Even if Your Majesty doesn't believe me,
you should trust Prioress Jingbai!
She saw it herself in the Temple of Pure Dew.
Dr. Wen frequently visited Noble Consort Lumière!
Amitābha. "The Buddha's disciples are forbidden to tell a falsehood."
Prioress Jingbai, what you just said
would make all Buddha's disciples feel ashamed to death of you.
Sister, it's late and you're still not back at the palace;
I've been so worried.
Are you all right?
I am.
I was on my way back to my palace to rest.
Then I encountered My Second Lady with a maid and a eunuch
saying they were looking for Noble Consort Lumière.
I saw the eunuch was Xiao-Yunzi.
Xiao-Yunzi said
he also had an acquaintance in the Temple of Pure Dew.
I was thinking
the words from Prioress Jingbai alone cannot be trusted.
It does no harm to hear from someone else.
So I gave the access tablet of my palace to Xiao-Yunzi
so he could bring in his acquaintance.
I didn't expect them to return so quickly.
They must have rushed their steps.
Your Majesty has banished my sister once.
Do you intend to banish her again?
There are other nuns in the Temple of Pure Dew.
Your Majesty should listen to them, too.
It's been years, Your Highness.
Has the frostbite on Your Highness's hands
been less severe this winter?
It's much better now,
but still hurts and itches in winter.
How is it that
you know about the frostbite on Noble Consort Lumière's hands?
The Noble Consort did all kinds of hard labor -
chopping wood and laundry - in the Temple of Pure Dew.
Her hands were immersed in the river even in the coldest months.
How could her hands avoid frostbite?
If she didn't obey, Jingbai would abuse her verbally or physically.
The Noble Consort often suffered illness and pain.
Jingbai even falsely accused her of stealing bird's nest,
and forced her to move to Peak Lingyun on a snowy day.
The Noble Consort almost didn't survive.
Your Majesty, if it wasn't for Dr. Wen's frequent visits,
Noble Consort Lumière might not even be here today.
So vicious! How can you claim to be the Buddha's disciple?
Jingbai is not that vicious; after all,
she did allow the Noble Consort to survive.
However, Peak Lingyun is isolated and difficult to travel to,
with many incidents of mountain cats attacking people.
If there was anything private between Noble Consort Lumière
and Dr.Wen, she could have moved away easily
instead of facing the hardships there.
Huan Huan, you've endured too much.
Lumière has suffered such injustice.
Your Majesty must impose stern punishment on this nun.
Your Majesty has discerning eyes.
I didn't mistreat Her Highness.
Tell me, what punishment do you suggest?
Your Majesty, this nun seems to have a vicious heart
and a provocative tongue for stirring up gossip.
Your Majesty must have her tongue pulled out
to satisfy Lumière's vengefulness.
I always thought Concubine An was a gentle person.
I would have never expected
your ruthless approach and merciless heart.
Noble Lady Délice, help me!
Noble Lady Délice, please help me! Noble Lady Délice!
Noble Lady Délice!
Please spare me, Your Majesties!
Your Majesty!
Prioress Jingbai claimed that she hadn't
stepped into the harem for two years.
Yet when I spoke to her,
she immediately knew me as a Noble Lady,
whose status was not high enough for a weighty oil lamp.
It's evident that she is well-informed about harem affairs.
Noble Lady Délice must have worked hard
trying to recruit each one of you!
My Lady... My Lady!
I'm so sorry, My Lady.
My Lady...
I had no choice but to come here...
Otherwise Lady Délice...
Lady Délice will tell Chen Si to beat me to death.
My Lady...
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
Even though My Lady knew Dr. Wen since they were young,
Your Majesty, they do not hold the slightest private feelings between them!
Your Majesty, please make a clear-sighted judgment!
Your Majesty,
Noble Lady Délice instructed Bin'er, Petunia and Jingbai to defame me.
This fact has manifested
"as if the covering has been removed".
I wonder if there is anyone behind Noble Lady Délice.
She doesn't have the audacity to plot this on her own
or the acumen to think of everything.
I agree with Noble Consort Lumière.
If we allow this person to continue
"creating winds and waves" in the harem,
I'm afraid our life in the harem still won't be peaceful.
I hope Your Majesty can address it soon.
Noble Lady Délice,
if you confess the mastermind behind this,
I might consider sparing you.
The choice to save your own life
is now solely in your hands.
No one instructed me.
It's because I hate you bitterly, Noble Consort Lumière.
Is it?
Ever since the rise of the Gūwalgiya clan,
your father envied my father and you hated me bitterly.
My family is not involved!
Am I inferior to you in my background or my appearance?
Why do you get all the glory before His Majesty?
So ... It was all my own idea!
How nice to have one's own sister in the harem.
Seeing Noble Consort Lumière with her own sister...
It reminds me of the time
when my sister and I served Your Majesty together in your estate.
Being with one's own sister...
Whether it is misfortune or blessing,
at least there would be one person who trusts me.
Your Majesty,
if Première was still here with me,
she would surely believe
that I am innocent.
How I wish
that Première never had such a sister as you.
If I knew that the water was...
Your Majesty, I didn't mean to.
When Her Majesty was getting the water, I helped carry the bowl.
I forgot that I was rinsing alum rocks in the yard,
and my finger touched the water accidentally.
It was my unwitting mistake, Your Majesty.
Spring was careless in her duty.
Banish her to the Department of Penalty.
Help me! Your Majesty!
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
You may rise.
I still haven't heard anything from the Palace of Great Benevolence.
And Dr. Wen hasn't come back.
Lunar, go inquire about what is going on.
Yes.
Your Highness, terrible news.
The Palace of Great Benevolence is in chaos.
Noble Consort Lumière suffered a great grievance.
Concubine An sent me to deliver the message.
What did you say?
Noble Consort Lumière suffered a great grievance ...
For what?
Lady Délice claimed that the Sixth Prince is the child of Dr. Wen.
My Lady! My Lady!
Allow me to take my leave.
Get the sedan ready.
I'm going to the Palace of Great Benevolence.
My Lady, you can't go there.
If what Sparrow said is true,
going there will affect your prenatal qi.
It's not the time to talk about this.
Is it enough to only care for myself?
If His Majesty believes those "small women"
and thinks that Huan'er commited adultery with Shichu,
my pregnancy will be truly affected!
Go! Go now!
Yes.
Hurry.
Lady Délice of the Gūwalgiya family
invented appalling rumors and disturbed the harem.
She is banished to the Cold Palace.
Attendant Kang and Concubine Fidèle
"chased the winds shadows of baseless hearsay."
Their stipend will be forfeited for the next six months.
I'll leave the rest to Noble Consort Lumière.
Jinxi.
Yes.
Take Bin'er and Moyan back.
Petunia
and Jingbai
will be flogged to death.
Your Noble Highness, please spare me!
Your Majesty, please spare me!
Ever since I returned to the harem,
there have been too many rumors about me and the twins.
I didn't administer punishment because I thought the rumors were ridiculous.
But I didn't expect that my forgiveness would brew today's crisis.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.